Everyone deserves to be loved.
Strange Magic is a music, animation, family film directed by Gary Rydstrom.
A love potion works its devious charms on fairies, elves and the swamp-dwelling
Bog King as they all try to possess the potion for themselves.
Bog King (voice), played by Alan Cumming.
Marianne (voice), played by Evan Rachel Wood.
Sunny (voice), played by Elijah Kelley.
Dawn (voice), played by Meredith Anne Bull.
Roland (voice), played by Sam Palladio.
Sugar Plum Fairy (voice), played by Kristin Chenoweth.
Strange Magic is a 2015 American animated jukebox musical fantasy film directed by Gary Rydstrom, screenplay written by Rydstrom, David
Berenbaum, and Irene Mecchi based on story written by George Lucas and inspired by William Shakespeare's A Midsummer Night's Dream.
The film stars the voices of Alan Cumming, Evan Rachel Wood, Elijah Kelley, Meredith Anne
Bull, Kristin Chenoweth, Maya Rudolph, Sam Palladio, and Alfred Molina.
It follows the leader of the Dark Forest known as the Bog King, who hates the notion of love and
orders the destruction of all primroses, a flower used to create love potions.
However, he begins to change his mind upon meeting the feisty fairy princess
Marianne whose heart was broken by her philandering fiancé Roland.
Meanwhile, the elf Sunny seeks to have a love potion made so he may
make Marianne's sister Dawn fall in love with him.
George Lucas, who had long wanted to make a film for his three daughters, had been developing the project for
15 years before production began, and described the film as Star Wars for a female audience.
The musical score was composed by Marius de Vries, and the soundtrack
consists of numerous historical pop songs spanning several decades.
Strange Magic was released in theaters in the United States
on January 23, 2015, by Touchstone Pictures.
The film received negative reviews from critics and was a box-office bomb,
grossing $13.6 million against a $70–100 million budget.
The film explores themes of elves, fairy, musical,
aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger.